# **OWAIS RAFIQ**

## Software Engineer | Bangalore, India

+91-7780817803 | peerzadaowais36@gmail.com | https://32oq.github.io/owais-rafiq

# **PROFILE SUMMARY**

Highly motivated and hard-working Software Developer with 1.5 years of experience in software development with a track record of success creating Applications and systems that are both well-received and commercially viable. Exploring my expertise and applying my skill set in diverse opportunities

#### **TECHNICAL STRENGTH**

**Technologies:** JavaScript (Nodejs), C, C++

Webservices: REST

Frameworks: Express JS

Web Technologies: HTML, CSS, Java Script, Nodejs, mongodb, Sql

**Database:** MySQL, Mongo dB

**Tools:** SDLC (Agile), GIT, Postman

## **PROJECT EXPERIENCE**

**Product Name:** Marketplace **Role:** Software Engineer

**Environment:** Nodejs

**Tools Used:** Vs Code, Gitlab, Postman, Sqlyog, nosql booster

**Duration:** Jan 2022 -present

This application provides online solution to different shop owners, doctors, teachers, buyers, sellers and other Organisation.

- Responsible for REST API's
- Responsible For Debugging existing API's errors

Product Name: ReferandEarn
Role: Software Engineer

**Environment:** Nodejs

**Tools Used:** Vs Code, Gitlab, Postman, Sqlyog, nosql booster

**Duration:** Jan 2022 -present

This application provides an earn option to the users when the refer it to someone.

Responsible for REST API's

Responsible For Debugging existing API's errors

**Product Name:** NatureCaptures **Role:** Software Engineer

**Environment:** Nodejs

**Tools Used:** Vs Code, Postman, mongodb

**Duration:** July 2020 – April 2021

This application provides online solution to different Artists and Art lovers. This project was meant for our final year Project

- Responsible for REST API's
- Responsible login logout API (Hashing, Salting)
- Responsible for frontend

#### **WORK HISTORY**

JUSTDIAL | Software Developer, Mar 2022 – Present

# **EDUCATION**

Bachelors Of Technology in Computer Science And Engineering 2017 - 2021